Akshit Bhandari

Ph: +91-9910285099 and +1(302) 588-8172 **Email:** akshit.rbhandari@gmail.com

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/akshitbhandari/

Profile

- ▶ Experienced Product Manager/Senior IT Systems/Business Analyst with 3+ year track record of managing products/ projects and analyzing data and defining key business requirements in tandem with Business Intelligence technologies and reporting tools
- Outgoing, detail oriented, and proficient at building consensus, creating and maintaining professional relationships, and eliciting clear decisions from clients and all levels of stakeholders

Technical Skills

COURSES - Udemy: Salesforce Administation Certification Course - 2018

CERTIFICATION - Microsoft: Analyzing and Visualizing data with Power BI - 2017

BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE - Requirements Gathering, Agile/Waterfall, Business Requirements, SQL, Functional Specifications, SQL, JAD Sessions, Test Cases, UAT, Project Coordination, BI Dashboards, Gap Analysis, Data Analysis, Use Cases, User Stories, Wireframes, Mockups, Change Management, SharePoint, Office 365, ODBC connectors

TOOLS - MS Power BI, Tableau, SAP Lumira, MS Visio, JIRA, WordPress, Bootstrap, Adobe Dreamweaver, Wix

SOFTWARE and DATABASES - Apache Hadoop, SAP Hana DB, MS SQL Server, Oracle DB, MS Access, Microsoft Office Suite, SAP Lumira, SAP HANA Studio, Balsamiq Mockups, MS Project

Experience

SPECIFIC SOLUTION INC, WILMINGTON, DE, USA

AUGUST 2018 - CURRENT

PRODUCT MANAGER

Product - Kairos - Small business loan CRM platform targeted for banks, credit unions, and business development companies (BDC) to **improve access to credit for small businesses across United States**

- Participate in gathering/understanding unique customer requirements and needs for both internal and externalfacing websites, workflows, and applications to meet customer demands and payment systems
- ▶ Define and build reports and dashboards leveraging Power BI for management decisions. Answer ad-hoc analytic questions, contribute to decision-making through opportunity sizing, and train users to self-serve Power BI reports
- ▶ Developing, designing and testing the solution in Salesforce, developing systems to automate the loan processes for Small Businesses from collecting documents to getting loan's approved

SOLAR TURBINES INC, SAN DIEGO, CA, USA

MAY 2018 - JULY 2018

PROJECT MANAGER/BUSINESS ANALYST

Project - **Decommission** LiveLink - **Document management & storage system** and **migrate** the active content to Office 365 tools such as **One Drive, Teams and Sharepoint** with its **metadata** at a global level

- Generate innovative approach to minimize/nullify downtime between transition for stakeholders (data owners)
- ▶ Design the strategy for a smooth transition of data from legacy to new tools
- ▶ Perform impact analysis on Intranet for Livelink links to map source and target links for legacy redirector
- ▶ Monitor workflow, make timeline adjustments, develop sprint review reports and perform backlog refinement

KPIT SEPT 2015 - FEB 2018

SAN DIEGO GAS AND ELECTRIC - SENIOR BUSINESS ANALYST, SAN DIEGO, CA, USA

FEB. 2017 - FEB. 2018

Project - **Data Analytics** - **Forecast the common types of distribution asset failures** to reduce the future impact on utility customers. The project ingested data from multiple sources including GIS, failure and asset information into the **Hadoop Distributed File System** and report off from **Power BI**

- ▶ Lead the project on shore and provide guidance to the offshore team of eight people
- Lead user sessions to storyboard the services, document business requirements, and perform gap analysis
- ▶ Collaborated with users and stakeholders to define, analyze, recommend, and implement optimal system workflows to address business requirements
- ▶ Design and develop Power BI interactive dashboards via connecting using ODBC connectors
- Manage alignment with stakeholders on business requirements, resource requirements, prioritization, and balancing of competing priorities
- Write SQL queries and work on SQL Server, Oracle DB, EDW, and SAP Hana to query data for analysis

MURPHY USA - BUSINESS ANALYST AND DEVELOPMENT LEAD, EL DORADO, AR, USA

JULY 2016 - JAN. 2017

Project - **Fuel Pricing Tableau dashboards** - Automation of comparison of current overall sales with its Same Day Last Year (SDLY) and Last Week(SDLW) sales along with the **drill down capabilities** to go to **store level** information. The dashboards would give near time data to decide the fuel selling price via a **live connection to the SQL DB**.

- ▶ Lead and implement complex project solution by guiding the project team towards successful project delivery
- Follow Daily Scrum process and responsible for ensuring timely and accurate artifacts maintained by the team in project repository on SharePoint as well as perform defect analysis and take corrective and preventive actions
- Elicit business requirements and document ETL business rules and convert into Functional Specification Document
- ▶ Coordinating the offshore activities and providing the team of five guidance on day to day activities
- ▶ Played a key role in defining, documenting and implementing key data governance processes
- ▶ Lead the mockup creation of the Tableau dashboards and developed functional requirements to show current sales data and to compare with its SDLY and SDLW
- Lead the Analysis, Coding, Testing, Maintenance and Enhancement of Tableau Dashboards and Data Lake
- ▶ Standardized business processes and key metrics within the corporation.

SAN DIEGO GAS AND ELECTRIC - BUSINESS ANALYST, SAN DIEGO, CA, USA

SEPT. 2015 - JUNE 2016

Project 1- Predictive Workforce Forecasting - Automate the process of forecasting for the electric distribution by loading the data from different data sources onto SAP HANA Database using ETL processes and running time series modeling in R to predict the best forecast using PAL Library in SAP HANA and report off from SAP Lumira.

Project 2 - Consolidate, Migrate and Upgrade Data Warehouses - Prepare a **business case** to decommission all supported and at risk environments within the scope by **leveraging Hadoop and traditional SQL Data Warehouses** with **minimal impact to the business users** and their reporting needs

- ▶ Drove the project for successful delivery of the same and saving \$10M that SDGE would have otherwise spent on contractors for completion of capital work
- Prepare business cases and perform Cost Benefit Analysis and estimate costs for the project
- ▶ Develop business flow diagrams, activity diagrams, and interaction diagrams in MS Visio
- > Perform GAP analysis of business rules, business and system process flows, user administration, and requirements
- Create specifications for the ETL developers to load the data to SAP HANA database, executed test scripts for the load of the database and aided in the escalation/resolution of data issues.
- Create reports in SAP Lumira to give a clear picture of workforce availability for other tasks

OFFICE OF RISK MANAGEMENT, CLEMSON UNIVERSITY, CLEMSON, SC JANUARY 2015 - AUGUST 2015

WEBMASTER/BUSINESS ANALYST

- Investigated and identified requirements via process flows, use cases, interviewing, and determining present state.
- Conducted and evaluated the information gathered through walk-through, requirements gathering meetings and worked with the stakeholders to ensure the right solution for their website
- Developed and designed user friendly website interface and attractive graphics using HTML5 and CSS3 http://www.clemson.edu/administration/risk
- Automated process that drastically reduced (~98%) the manpower necessary to acquire data for the federal OSHA Log on Workers' Compensation cases

INSTITUTE OF INTELLIGENT MATERIALS, SYSTEMS, & ENV., CLEMSON, SC

AUGUST 2014 - MAY 2015

RESEARCH ASSISTANT AND INTERACTION DESIGNER

- Integrated and programmed LED, distance, LCD screen and temperature sensors onto Arduino micro controllers
- Worked through the design and development cycle of CyberPLAYce in a multidisciplinary design-research team.
 CyberPLAYce https://cfacaa.human.cornell.edu/dea.arl/research-CyberPLAYce.html

PETROFAC, NEW DELHI, INDIA

MAY 2013 - JULY 2013

PROCESS ANALYSIS INTERN

- Carried out Load flow and Short circuit analysis on ETAP v11.0 on a Distribution Network
- Designed the indoor lighting of a building with light fittings of 2x36W SS for office use Chalmlite
- Worked on cable sizing, selection and layout for motors and transformer feeders for Saudi Arabian Oil Company,
 Jazan (Aramco Utility Project)

Education

CLEMSON UNIVERSITY, South Carolina, USA

August 2015

Major - Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering; Minor - Computer Science